Guide to the Rocky Clark Papers
Yale University Music Library
Rocky Clark Papers
1949-1976
MSS 132
Yale University Music Library
3.5
Rocky Clark was a journalist who wrote about the jazz scene in Southern Connecticut. As the first president of the Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut, his papers document the activities of this organization. Also represented in the collection is some coverage of the Intercollegiate Jazz Festival at Quinnipiac College. Clark collected a large number of jazz-related photographs for his features, which are also included in the collection.
Clark, Rocky, 1907-1990
Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut
Arrangement
The Rocky Clark Papers are made up of four series: I. Material related to the Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut; II. Material related to the Intercollegiate Jazz Festival at Quinnipiac College; III. Scrapbooks and Clippings; and IV. Photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Walter Rockwell "Rocky" Clark, Jr. (1907-1990), was a reporter and journalist in Southern Connecticut. He was born in Bridgeport, and attended Yale University (Class of 1930). Clark was a news editor at WNHG-TV, and an editor for The Bridgeport Post and the New Haven Register, where he wrote a weekly column on jazz. Clark was also the first president of The Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut. Founded in 1962, the Society was a non-profit organization dedicated to providing Dixieland jazz entertainment, and encouraged the playing of Dixieland jazz in Southern Connecticut. The Society published a newsletter called Jazz Echo, and sponsored many concerts in the area.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Rocky Clark was a journalist who wrote about the jazz scene in Southern Connecticut. As the first president of the Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut, his papers document the activities of this organization. Also represented in the collection is some coverage of the Intercollegiate Jazz Festival at Quinnipiac College. Clark collected a large number of jazz-related photographs for his features, which are also included in the collection.
Connecticut -- History, Local; Dixieland music -- History and criticism; Clark, Rocky, 1907-1990; Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut
- Material related to the Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut, 1949-1974
  Scope and Contents
  This series is divided into five subseries: Correspondence; Administrative files; Press releases and press packets; Flyers; and Jazz Band Echo.
  - Correspondence, 1943-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Contains correspondence to and from Rocky Clark.
  - Administrative files, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Contains by-laws, membership forms, meeting minutes, and other documents.
  - Press releases and press packets, 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Contains press releases for concerts sponsored by the Dixieland Jazz Society of Southern Connecticut, as well as press packets for performers.
  - Flyers, 1962-1974 (Box 1)
    Contains flyers for upcoming jazz concerts in various towns in southern Connecticut, sponsored by the Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut. Many of the concerts took place at Donat's Restaurant, in Milford, CT.
  - Jazz Band Echo, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Contains nine issues of Jazz Band Echo, published by the Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut.
- Material related to the Quinnipiac College Intercollegiate Jazz Festival, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Contains flyers, clippings, correspondence and photos related to the Quinnipiac College Intercollegiate Jazz Festival. The Festival's advisory board included Dave Brubeck, Stanley Dance, John Hammond, and Stan Kenton, among others. The Festival was directed by brothers Dominick and Sam Constanzo.
- Scrapbooks and clippings
  - Scrapbook 1, 1958-1959 (Box 2)
    Contains an assortment of newspaper clippings about jazz. Includes both national and local publications, such as Variety, Melody Maker, The Bridgeport Post and New Haven Register. Also contains photos and press releases.
  - Scrapbook 2, 1959 (Box 2)
    Contains clippings from Jazz Beat magazine.
  - Scrapbook 3, 1959-1961 (Box 2)
    Contains jazz-related clippings from a variety of publications. Also contains programs and flyers.
  - Scrapbook 4, 1962-1966 (Box 3)
    Contains an assortment of local newspaper clippings related to the Dixieland Society of Connecticut from 1962-1966. Also contains a notice mailed with Jazz Band Echo from Bob Fargo's home, May 9th, 1964, in regards to the disbanding of the Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut, as well as a letter sent to the members of the Dixieland Society of Southern Connecticut for membership in the Connecticut Traditional Jazz Club.
  - Scrapbook 5, 1966-1971 (Box 3)
    Contains local newspaper clippings related to the Dixieland Society of Connecticut from 1966-1971. Also contains multiple newsletters and a transcript of meeting notes.
  - Scrapbook 6, 1972-1976 (Box 3)
    Contains local newspaper clippings related to the Dixieland Society of Connecticut from 1972-1976. Also contains multiple newsletters and a transcript of meeting notes (loose).
  - Clippings, 1959-1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Jazz-related clippings from various newspapers and magazines.
- Photographs
  - Photos related to jazz in Connecticut, 1962-1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    This subseries also contains press releases and flyers from Connecticut-based jazz organizations.
  - Photos of Rocky Clark, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Publicity photos of musicians, arranged alphabetically (Box 4)
    - Publicity Photos: A (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Publicity Photos: B (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Publicity Photos: C - E (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Publicity Photos: F - G (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Publicity Photos: H (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Publicity Photos: J - L (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Publicity Photos: M - N (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Publicity Photos: P - R (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Publicity Photos: S, T, V, W, Y (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Publicity Photos, groups (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Jazz Beat photos (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photos of jazz musicians (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
    This subseries contains three folders of photographs, most of which are unidentified. Some are headshots of musicians that Clark may have gathered for his articles. Others are group photos of live performances, possibly in Connecticut.